Guide to the Edward E. Smuts Papers, 1945-1981 AIS.2012.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Regional Industrial Development Corporation (RIDC), 1949-1977; V.
  - Topical Folders, 1949-1964; 1.
    - Parks & Recreation – Herr's Island, unknown (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Penn-Central Railroad – Finance Street (Homewood), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania Department of Commerce, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Pennsylvania Department of Labor and Industry, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Pennsylvania Economy League, 1949-1962 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Pennsylvania State Planning Board, 1957-1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Philadelphia Industrial Development Corp. (PIDC), 1959 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh Industrial Development Council, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
    - Publication & Press Release, 1953-1959 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Research and Development, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Research and Development Syndicate, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Residential Development Analysis, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Regional Industrial Renewal Survey, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - RIDC- APA Study Scope & Procedures, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Ryan, Robert H., 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - State Action Program – Pittsburgh Region, 1959-1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - State of Connecticut Development Commission, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - United Fund of Allegheny County, 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Urban Land Institute – Correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Studies, and Proposals, 1956-1977; 2.
    The RIDC reports and studies found in this subseries appear to be used throughout Smuts' career and many date beyond his tenure with the agency. Many of these reports were used as informational tools to encourage companies to relocate to southwestern Pennsylvania. Included here are RIDC annual reports, studies on the expansion of the highway system around Pittsburgh, steep slope studies, and preliminary analysis of potential companies trageted for relocation.
    - "An Interim Report to the Directors Eight Months Operation of the Regional Industrial Development Corp.", May 1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "Statement on Industrial Area Renewal for the City of Pittsburgh, County of Allegheny and Other Counties of the Pittsburgh Region to the Senate Subcommittee on Housing", December 1957 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "A Report to Sponsors of the Regional Industrial Development Corporation: Progress 1955-1957 and A Program for the Future", October, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "The Pittsburgh Region Highway System and Future Economic Development", December 1958 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "A Study of Civic Agencies in the Pittsburgh Area, Adapting Civic Agency Structure to Meet Renaissance Needs", October 1958 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "A Report Submitted to the Industrial Panel, Urban Land Institute, 1958 for Consideration of the Problem 'How to Accomplish the Best Industrial Re-Use fo Blighted Urban Land'", May 1958 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Prospect Analysis: Research Centers in the Pittsburgh Economic Area", August 1958 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "Prospect Analysis Automotive Industry", August 1958 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "A Program for Continuing Economic Analysis in the Pittsburgh Region", February 1958 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "Working Toward an Industrial Land Policy and Program for the City of Pittsburgh", May 1958 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - "Prospect Analysis: A Survey of Can Manufacturing Facilities (Preliminary)", December 1958 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "Industrial Area Renewal Program Chateau West and Woods Run: R.I.D.C.'s Recommendations to the City Planning Commission and the Urban Redevelopment Authority", July 1958 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Highway Access Control Study: Pilot Study Route- U.S. 22- Monroeville to Congruity", November 1958 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - "Working Toward and Industrial Land Policy and Program for the City of Pittsburgh", November 1958 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - "Survey of Waterborne Traffic Patterns and Waterside Public Terminal Facilites in the Allegheny County Area: Volume 1 Narrative Report", October 1958 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - "Digest, Conference on Jobs and Business Climate in Pennsylvania", March 1959 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "Community of Interest Between the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Area and the Upper Ohio Valley a Preliminary Analysis", 1959 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "Chartiers Industrial Districts a Proposal to Put Idle Land to Work, Preliminary Summary Report", September 1959 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Northeastern Industrial Developers Association, Salary, and Activity Survey", October 1960 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Program of the Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania", March 1962 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "First Annual Report 1962", September 1962 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "Six Month Report of the President Regional Industrial Development Corporation", July 1962 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - "A Progress Scrapbook", 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - "Report to RIDC Directors", April 1963 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - "First Annual Report 1963", August 1963 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - "Second Annual Report 1963", September 1963 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - "Pittsburgh Research - Key to Tomorrow", 1963 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - "Second Annual Report 1964 RIDC Industrial Development Fund", September 1964 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - "Third Annual Report 1964 Strategy for Growth" (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - "The Southwestern Pennsylvania Region is on the Move", July 1964 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - "The Manpower Development and Training Act and Southwestern Pennsylvania", April 1964 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - "The President's Committee on Equal Opportunity in Housing and the Greater Pittsburgh Housing Conference", November 1965 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - "Third Annual Report 1965" (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - "Fourth Annual Report 1965, Growth Through Technological Change" (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - "Fourth Annual Report 1966", August 1966 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - "Fifth Annual Report 1967", August 1967 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - "The Human Resource, a Changing Regional Pattern 1968 Annual Report", January 1968 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - "Sixth Annual Report 1968", August 1968 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - "Public/Private Investment Partnership for Growth in the 70's, 1969 Annual Report" (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - "The Changing City Report, Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh", June 1969 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - "Seventh Annual Report 1969", September 1969 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - "Geo-Economic the Geographic factor in Economic Growth 1970 Annual Report", January 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Eighth Annual Report 1970", August 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Transition of a Region Southwestern Pennsylvania's Changing Economy, 1971 Annual Report", September 1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Ninth Annual Report 1971", August 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Turnaround Employment Patterns in a Changing Economy, 1972 Annual Report", August 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Tenth Annual Report 1972", September 1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Eleventh Annual Report 1973", September 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Twelfth Annual Report 1974" (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Diversification and Economic Opportunity 1975 Annual Report", August 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Thirteenth Annual Report 1975", August 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Fourth Annual 1976", October 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "Fifteenth Annual Report 1977", August 1977 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Pittsburgh Region Limited Access Highways", unknown (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "The Pittsburgh Region Highway System and Future Economic Development - A Confidential Preliminary Report", unknown (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Analysis of the Preliminary Engineering Report Recommended Route for FAI-15 Washington to Warrendale Interstate Route", unknown (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Steep Slope Renewal Report Appendices", unknown (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "RIDC Industrial Park, Allegheny County Suburban Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", unknown (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "Thorn Hill Industrial Park Allegheny County Butler County Suburban Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania", unknown (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Proposed Pittsburgh Research Center Bituminous Coal Research, Inc.", unknown (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Related Professional Materials, 1950-1979; VI.
  This series contains a variety of subject and project files that do not clearly related to the various professional positions held by Smuts. Clearly Smuts had some involvement in these projects but the relationship is not clearly evident in all cases.
  - Allegheny County Indstrial Information, 1950-1958 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - American Society for Public Administration - Meeting and Reports, 1966-1973 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Noise Pollution: The Rising Racket, (Audio tape), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Breskin, Joseph - Westmoreland County, unknown (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Butler County, Pennsylvania, 1952-1958 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Byers, A.M., unknown (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Cohen, Larry - Monroeville Project, unknown (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - County Information, unknown (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - CRP, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Detter, Ritchey, Sippel Associates, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Designers Center, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Disposition Procedures, January 1961 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Downtown Projects - Penn Station, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Doziadas Association, unknown (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Dun & Bradstreet Reports, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Empire Fund, Inc. - Director's Meeting, May 8, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Greater Harrisburg Movement, Inc., 1973 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Heinz Warehouse -#1, unknown (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Housing Authority of the City of Pittsburgh, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Housing Market Analysis, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Johnson, Howard, unknown (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Lawrence Paint Company Building Project, unknown (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Lutheran Brotherhood Fund, Inc., 1964 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Maps, unknown (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, unknown (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Photographs, unknown (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Pittsburgh Comprehensive Plan and Development Program, unknown (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - S. S. Kressge Company, unknown (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Steel City Electric, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Steep Slope Renewal, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Urban Design Consultants, Inc. - Clifton Park, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Vacation of Streets, unknown (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Vacant/Sensitive "Neighborhoods for Living" Center, unknown (Box 10, Folder 52)
- Urban Development Consultants, Inc., 1959-1981; VII.
  The Urban Development Consultants series documents the primary consulting firm founded and operated by Smuts. The firm's primary clients include public, civic and private development organizations within the Greater Pittsburgh region.
  - Environmentally Sensitive/Predominately Vacant, 1964-1980; 1.
    Smuts actively participated in the development of Greenway projects by evaluating Environmentally Sensitive/Predominately Vacant areas of Pittsburgh. The subseries focus on various projects, land leases, studies that relate to the vacant land areas. Included in the folders are agenda of meetings, program and project proposals, annual reports, notes, analysis, blueprints, budget and service expenses.
    - Concept - Environmentally Sensitive/Predominately Vacant, unknown (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Acquisition Cost Techniques, 1971-1978 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Aerials Photography, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Area Analysis Summaries, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Bigelow Acquisition Owner/Assessment, unknown (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Department and Agencies - City Planning, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Department and Agencies - Environmentaly Services, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Department and Agencies - Housing, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Department and Agencies - Housing Authority, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Department and Agencies - Land and Buidlings, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Department and Agencies - Mayor and Council, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Department and Agencies – Miscellaneous Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Department and Agencies - Parks and Recreation, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Department and Agencies - Public Works, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Department and Agencies - Urban Redevelopment Authority, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Department and Agencies - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Earlier City-Wide Property, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Handout References, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hazelwood, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Other Area Examples, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Phase II Preliminary Analysis Methods, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Richard King Mellon Proposal/City of Pittsburgh/Steep Slopes/River frontage, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Richard King Mellon Foundation Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Scaife Foundation - City Proposal, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Slide Show, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Spiegel, Ben, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Zoning Controls, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Financial, 1959-1976; 2.
    This subseries includes invoice reports, financial ledgers, consulting time sheets, and employee payroll and expense reports.
    - Allegheny County Planning Commission - Contractual Details, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Allegheny County Planning Commission - Consulting Activities Reports, 1959-1965 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Bibliographies, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Duquesne Light Company - Consulting Activity Reports, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Federated Funds, Inc. - Board of Directors Activities, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Financial Aids for Urban Development (Course UA-251), Pitt GSPIA, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Financial Statments (Urban Development Consultants), 1971-1976 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - National Association of Real Estate Boards (NAREB)- Building America Better Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Margiooti, Rose E., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Mayor's Office - City of Pittsburgh, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Employees - Urban Development Consultants, Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Slocum, Robert J., 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Waddell, William B., 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Greenway Projects, 1977-1981; 3.
    This subseries contains documentation on multiple greenway projects that the UDC consulted on. The contents include area maps, blueprints, appraisal reports of property, lot and block order lists, project proposals, correspondence, gift of property procedure with documentation, pubic property transfer outline, reports, notes, newspaper clippings, budget reports, and project proposals. Some photographic materials are also included in project files. The images depict residential lots, aerial views, and neighborhood views.
    - Becks Run Greenway, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Beechview and Mt. Washington Phase 1, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Bigelow and Polish Hill, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Charles Street Area, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Conrail, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Fifth and Forbes Corridor Maps, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Fifth and Forbes Parkway Corridor Property Data, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Fifth Avenue Greenway Project, 2300-2500 Block Photographs, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Greenway Brochure Distribution, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Greenway Project - Clarke Thomas Follow-up, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Hazelwood and Greenfield Greenway, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Liberty Tubes (Tunnel) South Greenway, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - PMMP - Greenway Publication Materials, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway - David Cirocco, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway - Joseph Garbowski Property, unknown (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway - Salago Property, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway - Treatment Area Phase II, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway I, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Spring Hill and Spring Garden Greenway II, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Health System Agency, 1970-1979; 4.
    The UDC created a subsidiary component entitled the Health Systems Consultant to work with the Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, which studied the health care needs and services of the region. The contents include facility studies, program and project agendas, budget reports, meeting notes, program improvement plans and reports, hospital occupation statistics, hospital trustee's seminar, and agreements.
    - 4 Hospital Dialogue- Joint Advisory Committee Meeting, 1970-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Advisory Group Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County Hopstials - HSA and Health System Consultants, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bergholz, David and George Taber, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Clem, John, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Contract and Services Rendered by Urban Development Consultants, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Facility Study and Planning Process, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Facilities Development Plan, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Follow-up, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Materials, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Health System Consultants, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Hospital Occupancy Reports, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Obstetrical Outline HSA and HSASP, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Preliminary Special Projects Outline, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Regional Health Facility Study, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Reports and Maps, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Shared Services Potential for Sub-areas - Fayette, Greene, and Washington, 1975-1978 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Southern Allegheny County Hospital Association (SACHA) - Long Range Plan Development, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Staff Education and Training Sessions, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - United States Officials and Health System Agencies, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - JDJ Associates, 1973-1985; 5.
    UDA worked in association with the JDJ Associates on a redevelopment project focused on Craig Street in the Oakland neighborhood of Pittsburgh. The project inlcudes documentation on commercial development of the street.
    - Appeal, John and Jon Humphrey - Lease, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Balance Sheet January, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Craig Square Shops, 1975-1978 (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
    - Current Financing, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Economic Analysis, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Equity Investment, 1978-1985 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial Analysis, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Financial Reference I, 1973-1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Financial Reference II, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Gallery Shops Tenants, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - J.Harger - Juniper Hollow Gallery, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - JDJ Associates - General, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Joint Venture - JDJ, Joel H.Kranich, and Lawrence N. Adler, 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Joint Venture - South Craig St., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Miller, Simon, and Wolf - Gallery Shops, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Nierenberg, John - High Society Snacks, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Partnership Proposals, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Sturgeon, Everatt - La Ventana Sur, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Oakland Directions Inc., 1970-1980; 6.
    This subseries includes documentation on the planning process to produce a redevelopment plan for the Oakland neighborhood of Pittsburgh during the 1970's. Included are committee meeting agendas, meeting notes, memorandums, general reference materials, and proposals.
    - AD Hoc Committee, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Darragh/Terrace Triangle, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Implementation Program for Planning and Development, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Magee Project, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Oakland Directions Inc. - General, unknown (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Oakland Planning Studies, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Oakland Preliminary Draft Report, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Opportunity Areas, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Panther Hollow, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Planning Committee, 1974-1980 (Box 13, Folder 24-27)
    - Planning Committee - Follow-up, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Planning Committee - Goals and Guidelines, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Planning Committee - Handwritten Notes, unknown (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Planning Committee - January Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Planning Process Drafts, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Planning Project Proposal, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Short-Range Proposals, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Supplemental Funding, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Transportation, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Transportation Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Urban Design Associates, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Conklin & Rossant", unknown (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "A Proposal: Planning for Oakland's Future", April 1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "A Master Plan for the Oakland Area - A Proposal to the City Planning Department and Oakland Directions, Inc.", April 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Planning Oakland's Future Phase II", May 1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Proposal to City of Pittsburgh Department of City Planning and Oakland Directions, Inc. for Planning and Urban Design Services", May 1977 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "Oakland Area Pittsburgh - A Proposal to Prepare a Growth Management Master Plan", May 1977 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "Planning Oakland's Future Phase 2", May 1977 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Studies, and Proposals, 1960-1981; 7.
    The subseries consists of reports, studies and proposals that were either produced by Smuts or were used in conjunction with projects undertaken by his firm.
    - "Land for Industry", May 1960 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "The Allegheny Seminar - Agenda Guide "The Movement of People and Goods in Allegheny County", April 1961 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - "The Allegheny Seminar - Agenda Guide "The Environmental Pattern in Allegheny County", April 1961 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "Re-Use Value Appraisal, City of Meadville Redevelopment Area R 22 - Supplement to Land Utilization and Marketability Study", September 1961 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - "Review of the Stadium Urban Renewal Project and Recommended Financing Proposal", September 1962 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Winthrop Urban Renewal Project - New London, Connecticut", October 1963 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "Land Utilization and Marketability Study - General Hospital Urban Renewal Project - W.VA. R-12", November 1963 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Proposal for Selective Counselling on Land Utilization and Marketability Gladstone Urban Renewal Project", December 1963 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Second Year Activites and Progress Greater Cleveland Growth Board 1963 Annual Report", February 1964 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - "Land Utilization and Marketability Study - Canonsburg, Pennsylvania - General Neighborhood Renewal Plan PA. R-132", June 1964 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Comprehensive Development Plant - The Chartier's Panhandle Region", August 1964 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - "Proposal for the City of Pittsburgh Participation in the Project 70 Program", October 1964 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - "Land Utilization and Marketability Study -Scottdale Plaza PA. R-189", October 1964 (Box 14, Folder 31)